CURRICULUM VITAE

Gourav Prasad Nunia

Associate-Data Science

+91 8420129035 gouravprasad83@gmail.com Bengaluru, IN

Highly motivated and passionate Analytics Expert who is specialized in translating real world business challenges into Analytics Frameworks and delivers strategic recommendations back to the client. Has experience in delivering end to end Data Science Project from Ideation to Evaluation and Model Deployment involving complete Data Science Lifecycle with total work experience of 3 years & 3 months.

Skills

Machine Learning

Classification Algorithm: Logistic Regression, Decision Tree, Random

Forest, K-NN, SVM.

Regression Algorithms:,

Linear Regression, Decision Trees,

Random Forest, SVR.

Clustering Techniques: K-Means,

Hierarchial.

Forecasting: Time Series

Dimensionality Reduction: PCA, LDA

Text Analytics/NLP

TF-IDF,
Sentiment Analytics. Sen

Sentiment Analytics, Sentiment Analysis of products feedback.

Statistical Analysis

EDA, Inferential Statistics, Hypothesis Test, T-test, ANOVA, ANCOVA, Outlier Detection, Inter-Quartile Ranges, Sampling Techniques, Boxplot

Tools/Languages

1. Languages: Python, SQL,

Matplotlib, Seaborn

2. Visualization Tools/Lib: Tableau,

Databases

MySQL

Others

Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Power Point, JIRA

Work Experience

Cognizant (Associate-Data Science), January 2019 ~ Present

- Credibility Analysis of a new product (policy) launch- The problem was to estimate if a customer would opt for an enhancement in the policy which Liberty Mutual is about to launch in this feature or not. The basic idea was to automate the calling and product description process to each customer associated with them.
 Skills/Libraries: Python, Machine Learning Models - Random Forest, CART, Logistic Regression, Scikitlearn, Matplotlib, Seaborn.
- 2. <u>Clustering of Product Parameters</u>- The problem was to identify the buyers purchasing behavior and divide them on the basis of the products they have previously bought from Nike in order to create a strategy for the customers to make them buy different and similar products.

Skills/Libraries: Python, Machine Learning Models - Clustering-K means, Hierarchal Clustering, Scikitleam, Matplotlib, Seaborn.

3. <u>Sentiment Analysis</u> - The assignment was to evaluate customer's response towards products of a Nike-Air genre which was achieved through judging the sentiment of comments and feedbacks of the product users in order to help the client to get a better idea in launching a product similar to Nike-Air.

Skills/Libraries: Python, Machine Learning Models - NLP, TextBlob, TF-IDF, Scikitlearn, Matplotlib, NLTK.

Deployment flow: Data Ingestion > Data Enrichment > Exploratory Data Analysis > Statistical Model Building > Model Evaluation > Deployment.

Cognizant (Analyst-Data Science), January 2018 ~ December 2018

Writing Complex Queries for data extraction from DB2 database | Cleaning the data in Excel and providing useful insights.

Skills Used: SQL.

Cognizant (Programmer Analyst Trainee), September 2017 ~ December 2017

1. Trained on programming language like Python and concepts of Statistics by cognizant learn team **Software Used**: Anaconda, Tableau

Project and Competitions Portfolio

Machine Learning & Statistics

- > Cancer detection using different classification models by checking the properties malignant and benign in cells.
- > HR Attrition Detection using Random Forest and Support Vector Regressor.
- Credit Risk Analysis using Decision Tree.
- House Price Prediction using Linear Regression.
- Predict Diabetes of a user from medical report using Logistic regression.
- Principal Component Analysis based on Cancer Diagnosis data.

Training Undertaken

Python, Machine Learning, SQL.

Education

B.Tech (Computer Science), Pailan College of Management & Technology, Kolkata (2012 ~ 2016).

 $\textbf{Declaration:} \ \ \textbf{I} \ \text{hereby declare that all the above information is correct and to the best of my knowledge}.$